Guide to the Dorsey and Whitney, LLP Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp Records TAM.509
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Dorsey and Whitney, LLP Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp Records
2004-2008
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Dorsey & Whitney, LLP
TAM.509
5 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
This collection documents the detention of six Bahraini men at the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp and their legal representation by a group of attorneys from the firm of Dorsey & Whitney, LLP. Included are correspondence, a variety of legal documents, and press from online and print sources.
Conditions Governing Access
Repository permission is required for access. Please contact the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, 212-998-2630.
Provenance
Donated by Dorsey & Whitney, LLP in 2009. The accession number associated with this collection is 2009.053.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically with the exception of court documents, which are arranged in chronological order. The collection is composed of the following 3 series:
Missing Title
Series I: Correspondence and Related Material, 2004-2007
Series II: Court Documents, 2004-2008
Series III: Press, 2004-2008.
Historical/Biographical Note
With approximately 650 lawyers and 850 support staff, Dorsey & Whitney, LLP, is the 60th largest law firm in the United States with 19 offices in the U.S., Europe and Asia-Pacific The firm's home base and its largest office is in Minneapolis. It offers services in more than 50 different areas of legal practice. Dorsey was a 1993 charter signatory of the Law Firm Pro Bono Challenge, which asks firms to contribute 3% of billable hours to pro bono work. As of 2008, Dorsey had met the challenge for 16 consecutive years. One of its many pro bono activities involved Guantanamo Bay detainees. At the request of the Center for Constitutional Rights in 2004, a team of Dorsey attorneys provided representation for six detainees from Bahrain.
In mid-2004 Dorsey lawyers filed an initial petition in the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia for writ of habeas corpus on behalf of the detainees (Isa Ali Abdulla Al Murbati, et al. v. George Walker Bush, et al.), beginning a process that lasted over three years. The case for the six Bahraini detainees was at times consolidated with others such as Khaled A.F. Al Odah, et al. v. United States of America, et al. and In re Guantanamo Detainee Cases, as there were many similar efforts underway to obtain for the detainees the right to challenge in federal courts their detention and conditions of confinement.
Dorsey attorneys visited the detainees a number of times at the Guantanamo Bay Camp and also traveled to Bahrain to meet with family members and government officials.
By August 2007 all six of the men had been released -- Adel Kamil Abdulla Haji (Al Wadi), Salman Bin Ibrahim Bin Mohammed Bin Ali Al Khalifa, and Abdullah Majed Sayyah Hasan Al Noaimi, in November 2005; Salah Abdul Rasul Ali Al Bloushi in October 2006; Jum'ah Mohammed Abdul Latif Al Dossari in July 2007; and Isa Ali Abdulla Al Murbati in August 2007.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Guantanamo Bay Detainee Collection: Seton Hall University Law School Center for Policy and Research (TAM 472)
Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp (TAM 506)
Scope and Content Note
This collection describes the detention of six Bahraini nationals at the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp and their representation by a group of attorneys from the firm Dorsey & Whitney, LLP. The sequence of events is recounted in three series, each using a different medium to tell the detainee stories.
Series I: Correspondence and Related Materials, 2004-2007. A great deal of the correspondence in this series involves the attorneys (primarily Joshua Colangelo-Bryan) and the detainees. It relates the progression of the various cases as well as descriptions of detainee treatment at the camp. Colangelo-Bryan outlines difficulties encountered in arranging meetings with detainees, shares with the men information from their families, and attempts to improve their morale and provide emotional support. There are also letters to and from the Department of Justice concerning ongoing legal issues. A dialog between the Dorsey team and government officials of Bahrain is included as are letters written to U.S. politicians voicing opposition to legislation affecting the rights of Guantanamo detainees.
Many of the letters involve Ju'mah Al Dossari who writes in great detail about his treatment at the camp. Mr. Dossari attempted suicide on numerous occasions before he was finally released, once during a visit by Colangelo-Bryan. Notes describing that event are included in the series. There is also a folder containing photocopies of photographs taken during the attorneys' visit to Bahrain. The photos were shared with the detainees.
Series II: Court Documents, 2004-2008. This series provides a chronology of the detainees' Guantanamo experience and legal challenges. It begins with material from Combatant Status Review Tribunals and Administrative Review Boards for each detainee. The reports outline the Government's representation of the capture of each man and the justification for his incarceration. Lengthy statements by several of the detainees describe conditions at the camp, interrogations, experiences while in custody at other locations, hunger strikes and medical treatment.
The remainder of the series documents the various cases that continued from the initial petition for writ of habeas corpus through the release of each detainee and the resolution of Al Odah v. U.S.A and Boumediene v. Bush, Supreme Court cases with which the Bahraini appeals were consolidated and which resulted in a June 12, 2008, decision holding that the prisoners had a right to the habeas corpus under the U.S. Constitution and that the Military Commissions Act of 2006 was an unconstitutional suspension of that right. By the time of this opinion, all of the Bahrain detainees had been released.
(Note: The consolidated case Al Odah v. U.S.A. appears in two forms - one referencing case numbers 05-5064 and 05-5095 - 05-5116 and the other numbers 05-5117 - 05-5027. Because the first case grouping is much more frequent, it has been considered the default. This numeric annotation is reflected in the folder title only if the documents are associated with the second case reference.)
Series III: Press, 2004-2008. The final series contains many news articles and essays collected by Dorsey & Whitney that relate to Guantanamo detention and activities involving the six Bahraini detainees. In two of the folders are items from the Arabic language press; all of the remaining material is in English. Many of the news articles come from online sources, particularly Bahrain's Gulf Daily News.
In addition, there are online articles and photocopies of print articles from English language international sources such as the BBC News, Aljazeera.com, Prensa Latina, Guardian, International Herald Tribune and a number of middle eastern online newspapers. Much U.S. press coverage (online and print) is included, from such diverse sources as Mother Jones, Crain's, CNN.com, The Wall Street Journal, The New York Times, military sources (e.g. American Forces Information Services, The Wire and press releases from the Department of Defense), New York Newsday, The Washington Post, The Christian Science Monitor, USA Today, LA Times, Boston Globe and many others. There are printouts from websites such as Huffington Post, Democracy Now!, Common Dreams Newswire and The Raw Story.
Several lengthy essays from publications in the U.S. and the U.K. (e.g. The New Yorker, American Lawyer, The New York Review of Books, Harper's Magazine and The Telegraph) provide more detail and opinion. Press coverage from such a variety of perspectives helps give a more comprehensive overview of the experiences of the six Bahraini detainees in particular and the Guantanamo Detention Camp issues in general.
Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners and prisons, American.; Legal files.; Correspondence.; Clippings (information artifacts); Habeas corpus |z United States.; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp
- Series I: Correspondence and Related Material, 2004-2007.
  - Correspondence, Jul 2004-Aug 2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Sep 2005-Oct 2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Nov 2005-Apr 2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, May 2006-Feb 2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Mar 2007-Aug 2007 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Graham-Levin-Kyl Amendment, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Military Commissions Act of 2006 and Habeas Corpus, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Notes: Suicide Attempt by Jum'ah Al Dossari, Oct 14, 2005-Oct 15, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photographs (Photocopies), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Procedures for Visits with Detainees, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series II: Court Documents, 2004-2008.
  - Combatant Status Review Tribunal and Administrative Review Board: Al Bloushi, Salah Abdul Rasul Ali, 2004-2006 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Combatant Status Review Tribunal and Administrative Review Board: Al Dossari, Jum'ah Mohammed Abdul Latif, 2004-2006 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Combatant Status Review Tribunal and Administrative Review Board: Al Khalifa, Salman Bin Ibrahim Bin Mohammed Bin Ali, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Combatant Status Review Tribunal and Administrative Review Board: Al Murbati, Isa Ali Abdulla, 2004-2006 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Combatant Status Review Tribunal and Administrative Review Board: Al Noaimi, Abdullah Majed Sayyah Hasan, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Combatant Status Review Tribunal and Administrative Review Board: Al Wadi (Haji), Adel Kamel Abdulla, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Detainee Statements, 2005, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia: Al Murbati, Isa Ali Abdulla, et al.v. George Walker Bush, et al. - Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus (and Related Material), Jun 2004-Jul 2004 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Amended Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus (and Related Material), Aug 4, 2004-Aug 16, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Orders, Motions and Related Materials, Aug 17, 2004-Nov 10, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Individual Respondents' Motion to Dismiss, Oct 4, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Response to Habeas Corpus Petitions, Oct 4, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Respondents' Factual Returns to Petitions for Writ of Habeas Corpus, Oct 13, 2004-Oct 22, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Attorney Agreements and Declarations, Oct 18, 2004-Oct 19, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - U.S. District Court: In re Guantanamo Detainee Cases - Access to Factual Returns and "Protected Information", Oct 27, 2004-Jan 31, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush and In re Guantanamo Detainee Cases - Protective Order Issue, Oct 2004 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Respondents' Factual Returns to Petitions for Writ of Habeas Corpus, Nov 3, 2004-Dec 30, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - U.S. District Court: In re Guantanamo Detainee Cases - Protective Order and Counsel Access, Nov 4, 2004-Nov 8, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - U.S. District Court: In re Guantanamo Detainee Cases - Petitioners' Memorandum in Opposition to Respondents' Motion to Dismiss, Nov 5, 2004-Nov 15, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - U.S. District Court: In re Guantanamo Detainee Cases - Petitioners' Motion to Dismiss Claims Without Prejudice..., Nov 5, 2004-Nov 23, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - U.S. District Court: In re Guantanamo Detainee Cases - Respondents' Reply Memorandum in Support of Motion to Dismiss..., Nov 16, 2004-Dec 16, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Loss of Attorney Notes, Dec 23, 2004-Jan 14, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - U.S. District Court: In re Guantanamo Detainee Cases - Order Denying in Part and Granting in Part Respondents' Motion to Dismiss..., Jan 31, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - U.S. District Court: In re Guantanamo Detainee Cases - Petitioners' Joint Submission Regarding How These Cases Should Proceed, Jan 31, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - U.S. District Court: In re Guantanamo Detainee Cases - Motion for Leave to Take Discovery and for Preservation Order, Jan 2005 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - U.S. District Court: In re Guantanamo Detainee Cases - Orders and Pleadings, Interlocutory Appeal and Stay of Proceedings Pending Appeal, Feb 3, 2005-Feb 7, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit: In re Guantanamo Detainee Cases - Petition for Interlocutory Appeal, Feb 9, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Representation Authorization: Ameur Mammar, Feb 18, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: In re Guantanamo Detainee Cases - Additional Pleadings, Interlocutory Appeal, and Briefing Schedule, Feb 22, 2005-Mar 10, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush and Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Appeal Notice, Mar 14, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Pleadings and Opinion, Preliminary Injunction Enjoining Respondents from Transfer without Notification to Counsel, Mar 15, 2005-Apr 14, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - U.S. District Court: In re Guantanamo Detainee Cases - Unclassified Version of January 31, 2005 Opinion, Mar 17, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: In re Guantanamo Detainee Cases - Pleadings re: Appointment of Counsel, Apr 1, 2005-Apr 11, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah, Khaled A.F., et al. v. United States of America, et al. - Opening Brief for the U.S., Apr 27, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Washington Legal Foundation Brief as Amici Curiae, Apr 27, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Motion to File Joint Appendix and Various Orders, Apr 27, 2005-May 26, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Joint Appendix, Volume I (I), Apr 27, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Joint Appendix, Volume I (II), Apr 27, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Joint Appendix, Volume I (III), Apr 27, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Joint Appendix, Volume II (I), Apr 27, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Joint Appendix, Volume II (II), Apr 27, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Joint Appendix, Volume II (III), Apr 27, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Joint Appendix, Volume III (I), Apr 27, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Joint Appendix, Volume III (II), Apr 27, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Joint Appendix, Volume III (III), Apr 27, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. (Nos. 05-5117 - 05-5127) - Pleadings, Dismissing Appeal and Various Orders, May 16, 2005-May 31, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Public Joint Appendix (Copy 1), May 25, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Public Joint Appendix (Copy 2), May 25, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Supplemental Public Joint Appendix (Copy 1-Part 1), May 26, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Supplemental Public Joint Appendix (Copy 1-Part 2), May 26, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Supplemental Public Joint Appendix (Copy 2-Part 1), May 26, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Supplemental Public Joint Appendix (Copy 2-Part 2), May 26, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Brief for the Guantanamo Detainees, May 27, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Brief Amicus Curiae ... World Organization for Human Rights, May 27, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Reply/Cross-Appellee Brief for the U.S., Jun 17, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Reply Brief for the Guantanamo Detainees, Jun 28, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Pleadings, Orders and Related Material, Jul 8, 2005-Aug 2, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Filing and Counsel Substitution, Jul 2005 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. (Nos. 05-5117 - 05-5127) - Briefing Schedule, Sep 7, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Motions, Responses and Denial re: Temporary Restraining Order, Oct 4, 2005-Oct 11, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. (Nos. 05-5117 - 05-5127) - Opening Brief for the United States et al., Oct 17, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. (Nos. 05-5117 - 05-5127) - Public Joint Appendix, Volume I, Oct 17, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. (Nos. 05-5117 - 05-5127) - Public Joint Appendix, Volume II, Oct 17, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Filings, Motions, Declaration re: Temporary Restraining Order and Preliminary Injunction, Oct 31, 2005-Nov 7, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Respondents' Opposition to...Temporary Restraining Order and Preliminary Injunction, Nov 16, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Additional Pleadings re: Temporary Restraining Order and Preliminary Injunction, Nov 21, 2005-Dec 29, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. (Nos. 05-5117 - 05-5127) - Reply Brief, Dec 8, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Impact of Detainee Treatment Act of 2005, Jan 3, 2006-Jan 11, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Supreme Court of the United States: Hamdan, Salim Ahmed v. Donald H. Rumsfield... - Brief Amici Curiae of more than 300 Detainees..., Jan 6, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Amicus Curiae Briefs re: Detainee Treatment Act of 2005, Jan 25, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Briefing Schedule and Brief of Federal Parties re: Detainee Treatment Act of 2005, Jan 27, 2006-Feb 17, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Brief of Amici Curiae Senators Graham and Kyl in Support of Government (re: Detainee Treatment Act of 2005), Feb 17, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Supplemental Detainee Brief and Amicus Curiae Briefs re: Detainee Treatment Act of 2005, Mar 10, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Brief of Amicus Curiae Senator Carl Levin in Support of Petitioners re: Detainee Treatment Act of 2005, Mar 10, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals:Al Odah v. U.S.A.- Additional Pleadings and Orders re: Detainee Treatment Act of 2005, Mar 17, 2006-Mar 30, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - U. S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Application to Reinstate Motion for Temporary Restraining Order and Preliminary Injunction, and Denial Order, Jun 15, 2006-Jun 26, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Pleadings re: Effect of Hamdan v. Rumsfield, Jun 29, 2006-Aug 8, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - U. S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush and Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Pleadings re: Review of Certain Detainee Materials, Jul 7, 2006-Sep 20, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - U. S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush and Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Notice of Steps Taken in the Wake of Hamdan v. Rumsfield, Jul 7, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Supplemental Briefs Addressing Effect of Hamdan v. Rumsfield, Aug 8, 2006-Aug 15, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - U. S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Pleadings re: Review and Impoundment of Certain Detainee Materials, Aug 11, 2006-Sep 19, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Pleadings re: Notice of Transfer and Motion to Dismiss Case as Moot..., Sep 21, 2006-Oct 19, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - U. S. District Court: Counsel Changes, Sep 27, 2006-Jan 25, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Pleadings re: Significance of Military Commissions Act of 2006 (I), Oct 17, 2006-Dec 29, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Pleadings re: Significance of Military Commissions Act of 2006 (II), Oct 17, 2006-Dec 29, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - U.S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush and Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Notice of Military Commissions Act of 2006, Oct 18, 2006-Oct 20, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - U. S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Notice of Transfer of Petitioner Al Bloushi and Related Pleadings, Oct 26, 2006-Nov 15, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Letter on Behalf of Petitioner David Hicks, Dec 20, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - U. S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Pleadings List, Dec 27, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - U. S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush - Order Administratively Closing Case Based on Military Commissions Act of 2006, Jan 31, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Pleadings to Expedite Decision and Lift Stay, Feb 2, 2007-Feb 20, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Opinion of the Court and Dissenting Opinion, Feb 20, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Appendices (I), [Feb 20, 2007] (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Appendices (II), [Feb 20, 2007] (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Appendices (III), [Feb 20, 2007] (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Supreme Court of the United States: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Petition for Writ of Certiorari, with Appendix (I), Mar 5, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Supreme Court: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Petition for Writ of Certiorari, with Appendix (II), Mar 5, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Supreme Court: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Petition for Writ of Certiorari, Respondents' Brief in Opposition to Petitioners' Reply Brief, Mar 5, 2007-Mar [23], 2007 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Supreme Court: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Pleadings and Apr 2 Decision, Mar 5, 20007-Apr 2, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Supreme Court: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Brief Amicus Curiae of U.S. Senator Arlen Specter in Support of Petitioners, Mar 22, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. (Nos. 05-5117 - 05-5127) - Motion to Govern, Mar 2007 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Various Pleadings Addressing Continuation of Case, Apr 9, 2007-Apr 18, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Dossari, Jum'ah and Isa Al Murbati v. Robert M. Gates - Pleadings and Related Material (I), Apr 18, 2007-Jun 22, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - U. S. Court of Appeals: Al Dossari v. Gates - Pleadings and Related Material (II), Apr 18, 2007- Jun 22, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - U. S. District Court: Al Murbati v. Bush and Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Respondents' Motion to Dismiss Cases, Apr 19, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Supreme Court: Al Odah v. U.S.A. - Pleadings re: Suspension of Denial and Rehearing, and Order Granting Certiorari, Apr 23, 2007-Jun 29, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 22)